Saurabh Bajaj

saurabhbsd@gmail.com +91-8000888022

http://saurabhbajaj.me

SUMMARY

Saurabh is an experienced iOS application developer currently working in Pune, India. He likes to come up with simple solutions to difficult problems. Code quality, maintainability and pragmatism are his core programming principles. Being an iOS developer, he gives great attention to the UX and UI of the project.

EDUCATION

Master in Computer Applications *University of Pune*, Pune

Aug 2013 - Apr 2015

Bachelor in Computer Applications

July 2010 - Apr 2013

University of Pune, Pune

CERTIFICATIONS

Diploma in iOS Application Development

June 2014 - Aug 2014

Sourcekode Technologies, Pune

CAREER HISTORY

Software Engineer 2 - iOS, Amura Marketing Technologies, Pune

Sept 2018 - Present

- Own the complete product life-cycle from architecting to implementation and App Store release management.
- Handle a resource and ensure timely development and delivery of application with minimal bugs.

iOS Developer, Promobi Technologies, Pune

Nov 2015 - Sept 2018

- Own the complete product life-cycle from architecting to implementation and App Store release management.
- Worked on app performance optimisation by using profiling tools in Xcode.

iOS Developer - Intern, Emerson Innovation Center, Pune

Jan 2015 - Aug 2015

• Worked on a Bluetooth based application in Objective-C.

Apps

Brew Survey: A mobile survey and feedback solution

Handwerker Station: An ecommerce app

Booster: A snapshot of your finances at your fingertips

Naki: An innovative tech based laundry service.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Swift, Objective-C, C++, C, Python(minor experience)

Database: SQLite Version Control: Git

Libraries and Frameworks: Cocoa Touch, Core Data, Map kit, AVFoundation, Fabric, CoreBluetooth

Mobile Development: Native iOS Development

Operating Systems: macOS, Windows

Important links

Github: https://github.com/saurabhbajajcode

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/saurabhbajajcode/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/saurabhbajaj91

Volunteering Experience

Volunteer, National level Conference : Sinhgad Institute of Management and Computer Applications, (Pune)

Feb 2015